Marco Antonio Villanueva

React JS | JavaScript Developer- Cuernavaca, México

(+52) 777-1903773 marcovillanueva.m@gmail.com

GitHub: github.com/marco-villanueva LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/marcovillanuevamx/

Website: https://marcovillanueva.com/

React Developer 3+ years of experience handling different web technologies such as HTML, CSS, Wordpress 2+ years of experience, JavaScript 3+year of experience, jQuery, non-relational databases, React JS 3+year experience & VueJS 1+ year of experience.

EXPERIENCE

Globant, Web UI - React Developer Remote location. Oct 2021 - Present

- I worked on the development of an educational platform with an American client, using Strapi (a CMS headless), React JS, Javascript and Node JS.
- I've developed reusable components in ReactJS + NodeJS, as well as the modification of native and nonnative components of CMS, for example CKEditor, Math editors, Customs Media libraries, and others.
- I work with agile methodologies, peer code review and continuous deployments in applications. Always looking to take care of good practices in development.
- Tech-stack: React JS, Strapi 4, Node JS, Koa JS, PostgreSQL, REST API.

Search Rebel LLC, React Developer Remote location. California - USA — Apr., 2021 - Oct 2021

Search Rebel provides consulting services for software projects in any language, platform and vertical. With big emphasis on Big Data, Search Engines, Enterprise Systems and Databases.

- Migration of react components, from class components to functional components, implementing the use of hooks and Typescript.
- I implemented two payment methods for the USA and Mexico in a non-native technology, using JSON, React and Java. This allowed us to use the components dynamically for different pages and created documentation for each. This saves time in training new personnel and in creating learning content for application users.
- I worked on a project to migrate an e-commerce site to a multi-site created with Vue JS + Nuxt, creating reusable components for client's platforms and working with different teams using agile methodologies.
- Tech-stack: React JS, Vue JS, Figma, Java, Postman, JSON, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, GitLab, Git & Git-hub.

Web Developer - Freelancer — Jan, 2019 – Dec, 2020.

I worked for different clients on a freelance basis, with independent solutions such as websites for the presentation of their companies, or the implementation of sites for the presentation of virtual congresses. Some of the clients I have worked with: Amistad Live, Fiorillo Violins & Jorge Glez, Maiz de mi tierra.

Tech-stack: Wordpress, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Inkscape, Hosting Providers.

SKILLS

Programming Languages: HTML, CSS & JavaScript **Frameworks and Tools:** React JS, TypeScript, Postman,

Wordpress, Git & Git-hub.

Languages: English, Intermediate; Spanish, Native;

EDUCATION

Autonomous University of the State of Morelos – Cuernavaca, Morelos, México. Master's Degree in Educational Research 2014 – 2016

Autonomous University of the State of Morelos – Cuernavaca, Morelos, México. Mechanical Engineering Degree, 2007 – 2010